# Curriculum Vitae Of Md. Rakibul Al-Amin

E-mail: hasanrakib010@gmail.com

Portfolios: https://hasanrakib010.github.io/developer-portfolio/

https://sites.google.com/view/hasanrakib010/home

Mobile: 01775130083



#### **Objective:**

A self-motivated individual who wishes to give best effort in serving an organization where I can explore my analytical skills, academic qualifications and real-life experiences at various sectors in the competitive field of corporate world, learn new methodologies if needed in order to achieve success and develop a career opportunity.

#### **Experience:**

Lecturer of ICT (01/01/2019 - Continuing)
 Dr. Habibur Rahman IT School and College,
 Dapunia, Mymensingh.

# Trainings:

> 01/01/2019 - 30/06/2019

**Trainee** 

**Diganta Computer Training Center** 

Learned Basic Computer Applications

> 20/02/2019 - 30/05/2019

**Trainee** 

#### **PeopleNTech Institute of Information Technology**

Course on PHP language provided by the Govt. and Hi-Tech park of Bangladesh.

> 01/10/2020 - Ongoing

**Trainee** 

**LEDP** (Learning and Earning Development Project)

I am doing LEDP course provided by the Government of Bangladesh.

# **Academic History:**

Education	Result	Passing Year	Institution
M.Sc. (IT)	CGPA-3.88	Ongoing	Institute of Information Technology, Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka.
B.Sc. (CSE)	CGPA-2.83	2018	East West University, Aftabnagar, Dhaka
H.S.C	GPA-4.80	2013	Shahid Syed Nazrul Islam College, Mymensingh.
S.S.C	GPA-5.00	2011	Mukul Niketan High School, Mymensingh.

#### **Technical Skills:**

Programming Languages:	C, C++, C#, Python.
Scripting Languages:	PHP, JavaScript.
Design Experiences:	Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator, HTML, CSS.
Database systems:	MySQL, MongoDB.
Operating systems:	Windows 7/8/10, Linux.
Application Tools:	Microsoft Office, Excel, Power-Point

#### Special Skills:

- ✓ Capable of planning, organizing and executing effectively.
- ✓ Able to adapt with new environment and challenges.
- ✓ Good team worker with leadership skill.
- ✓ As an individual, I consider myself conscientious, honest and frank.
- ✓ Good team worker with leadership skill & fast learner.
- ✓ Can process the experience to deal with people from diverse culturalbackground in a very friendly manner.
- ✓ Like to face new people and environment.
- ✓ Have strong communication and interpersonal skills.

# **Certificates:**

- ✓ Bangladesh computer Society
- ✓ Zend Certified Engineering Training

# Language Proficiency:

Excellent communication skills both in English and Bengali Language.

# **Academic Projects:**

For our Final Project Presentation, I with my other 2 team members made a web app named: 'ORBIT' A Web App Using Classification Based Suggestion for Lost and Found

Items. Where we had to use different machine learning algorithms, PHP, Laravel, Python, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, BULKSMSAPI, GOOGLE MAP API etc.

➤ Me with my 2 other team-mates made "Online Diagnostic Center App" Using PHP, JQuery, MySQL, MDUI:

https://github.com/Hasanrakib010/Online-Diagnostic-Center.git

➤ I with my 2 other team-mates made the app named "Online Book Store" using PHP, Java-script, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap:

https://github.com/Hasanrakib010/Online-Book-Store.git

➤ I with my 2 other team-mates made "Meal Management System" App using Python, HTML, CSS:

https://github.com/Hasanrakib010/Meal-Management-System.git

I along with my 2 team members made a smart restaurant finder app using java in our Artificial Intelligence course, made a hospital management system app using C# in our Database Course, made a smart door lock system in Digital Logic design course, did a smart home automation project in our Microprocessor and Micro-electronics Course.

#### **Personal Interests:**

- Reading fiction books, News, Magazines
- Playing Football
- Watching movies

#### **References:**

Md. Moshiur Rahman Md. Shariful Islam

Area Manager, First Senior Assistant Director,

Mymensingh Region. Sales Division.

Akash DTH, Beximco Group. Walton Group, Bangladesh.

**Cell:** 01713241375 **Cell:** 01678049031

Email:rizonbd@gmail.com Email:shariful@waltonbd.com

# **Extra-Curricular Activities:**

Member of East West University Programming Club. (EWUCoPC)

Member of East West University Sports Club.

# Others:

**Father:** Late Abul Hashim **Mother:** Mst. Rabeka Sultana

Address: 28, Zilla School Road, Mymensingh

Cell: 01775130083; 01674557883

I do hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge.

Signature:

